

COLIN LEWIS

I am a UX Engineer. In this role I solve digital problems through the combination of over two decades experience as a designer, front end developer, illustrator, and writer. I work with Design Thinking to prototype and build websites that focus on user needs and make clients happy.

EXPERIENCE

Developer, Codeable Remote/Denmark · 2019-present

Codeable is an exclusive freelancer platform that connects businesses with premium WordPress developers.

My responsibilities as freelance designer and developer span the entire range of a web project: ideation, strategy and design, UX research and testing, prototyping, custom development, client education, and more.

Designer, Unlikely Objects AB Karlskrona, Sweden · 2017-present

Unlikely Objects is a storytelling studio that produces digital experiences and unusual books that combine literature, film, interactivity and delight.

Associate, Hoxby Remote/UK · 2019-2020

Hoxby is an exclusive group that provides custom, hand-picked teams of remote freelancers to large-scale and scale-up clients.

SKILLS

Adobe CS JavaScript
Affinity Designer PHP
Sketch WordPress
Hype Statamic
Invision Git

HTML5 Responsive design
CSS Accessibility
SASS WCAG

Soft skills:

Project and team management, concept development, prototyping, storytelling, creative problem solving. I have extensive training in creating and working with high-functioning teams, Susan Wheelan's effective team concepts, and the Co-Active leadership model.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web designer & developer Freelance · 2013-present

Web design & front end development, WordPress, strategy, branding.

Communicator, Tierps Municipality Tierp, Sweden · 2012-2013

Public information officer – PR and communications strategy in the Tierp Municipality Department of Culture. As Communicator I was responsible for investigating and serving the needs of all the Culture Department sections, including Children & Youth, Athletics, and the municipal library.

Web designer & developer Freelance · 2010-2012

Web design and front end development, WordPress. End to end project creation, supervision, development and delivery.

Consultant, Tierps Municipality Tierp, Sweden · 1997-2012

I organised and promoted the annual art festival *Konst på väg* in Tierps municipality together with the head of the Culture Department and a small team. I worked with marketing, strategy, and above all as designer and developer in the creation of the festival's website and printed catalogue. During my tenure, participation in the event increased over 500%.

Web designer, Fingerpaint Marketing Saratoga Springs, NY, USA · 2009-2010

Web design, front end development, web app UI and email marketing design, ExpressionEngine, WordPress.

Web designer & developer Freelance · 2002-2009

Web design & front end development, WordPress, ExpressionEngine.

EDUCATION

Interactive Design Foundation, Online/Denmark · 2020-present UX Designer path.

Hyper Island Karlskrona, Sweden YH · 2015-2017

Digital Media Creative is a program that allows students to develop their design, technological, management and entrepreneurial skills. I attended the learning hub in Karlskrona, Sweden.

University of Gävle Gävle, Sweden · 2005-2007 Creative writing in English.

LANGUAGES

English Swedish Beginning Portuguese